You know what functions are and you know where to find them, or at least where abouts to
find them and you know that they all together in little packages called modules. But now we need
a look at how do we actually use these function things? Okay, so I'm going to show you an example
where you can see that functions can really be very helpful and very important.
So the first thing we have to do if you want to use a function is you're going to have to
import the module that you would like to use, or you'll have to import the module of the
function you would like to use. Okay, so let me first tell you what we're going to be doing.
So what I want to do is I want to create a little mini application that generates random numbers.
So now if you think about this logically, I mean to code that would be pretty hard. How do I
have to code to give a random number? I mean, think about what you know, if statements,
else statements, but how can I make sure that every time this program is run? So I've tapped
the statement here that is basically importing the module random into this program that I'm about
to tap. So soon as I tap this here, I can use any of the functions found in the random module.
So let's get going. Okay, the function that I'm going to show you is going to
allow us to choose a range. So just say one in 10. And the name is when we run that program,
it will generate a completely random number between and including those two numbers.
So it will I'll tap it for you now, but basically it's going to be a number that can be
greater than or equal to one and less than or equal to 10. Okay, so it includes those two in numbers,
which might seem a bit different because before the in number wasn't included with other things,
but just remember random numbers, it includes both the beginning and in number,
but I'm going to show you that now. Okay, so now what we need to do is we need to create
a variable that is actually going to store that random number for us when the program runs.
So I'm just going to call it num and we are going to make num equal to a random number,
but of course if I wrote six and then went print six, I mean print num.
Very obviously, okay, that's not doing anything random. Every time I run it is, it is. Obviously,
you're going to be printing six because num is equal to six. I can't do that. I want to
change every time. So I'm going to do this. You're going to say random dot rand int and let's say
one at 10. Okay, so whatever just on him. So this first part here, that says random is the name
of the module we will be using to find the function. So what this is telling us when we say random,
it's saying to our program go and look in the random module that path and has stored. So it has
libraries and libraries and modules, but soon as it sees this, it's going to go, oh, I have to go
to the random module to find this function. Yeah, then the next thing after you've tapped this
random, you do this thing called a dot. So basically this dot is saying from the random module,
get this function. Okay, so whenever you're using functions, it's the same sort of thing every time
you're going to put the modules name that the function is from dot the function you want to use.
In this case, it's random. So now what is random is going to do? Or random does is it. Now,
every time I run the program is going to print a different number and that number is going to be
from an including one and to an including 10. So let's see what happens. And then I'm just printing
that number. So I'm going to run the program once. So what is it done? It's taken them and it's
assigned it to a random number over here. And how is it done that? I mean, we didn't have any code,
but obviously it's used this function. And that's what this function ran into that. So
really, I'm hoping you're saying that it is very helpful to use functions. Okay, so I just ran it
again. And now you see I've got five. So this down the program ran, it did this little random
magic over here. And again, picked a random number between there and assigned it to this
number value and then printed it. And then if I run it again, it's again, picked a random number
between and including those two numbers and assigned it to num and printed them. So each time
I run this program, a different number will be randomly generated. So yeah, that's pretty cool.
And that's an example of how to use functions. Now you'll even see in the game that we are
going to be coding at the end, we are going to in fact use this exact function and you'll see why
it is so important. So you can think about it in most games you play. The things that happen
or the things that players around you are doing if they are computer generated. So hopefully
you can see now while these are so cool. Well, while functions are so cool. They are allowing us to
use code by other people. That has already been pre-written, proofread, make sure it is the absolute
optimal code. And it's just allowing us to reuse it by using, by knowing the name. Okay. But
honestly, as you might have noticed, in order to use the function, you also have to know what
parameters it takes. So remember, I mentioned parameters earlier on. Basically parameters, each
function has certain parameters, it takes. So yeah, the parameters were this first one, which was
the starting point and the second one, which were the ending point. And the documentation I told
you about will also tell you what the parameters for the function are. So yeah, there's just a quick
example of a function and where you might use it. And from now on, I'm going to be using
functions a lot in our coding. And I'm actually going to show you how we could have used them
and lists and strings and all sort of examples. Some of them might be in the quizzes. So remember,
make sure you are doing those. And yeah, there is a brief and true to function.